Finding Aid for the Collection of 78 rpm 10-inch Records, approximately 1908-1950
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Collection of 78 rpm 10-inch Records, approximately 1908-1950
Mus. Arc. 86
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
1 box ( 40 sound recordings )
The collection contains 37 78 rpm 10-inch recordings, 1 7-inch 78 rpm recording, 1 5-inch 78 rpm recording, and 1 7-inch 45 rpm recording. The recordings are all commercial releases consisting of classical, ethnic, and popular music.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Compiled by staff of the State University of New York at Buffalo, Music Library.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Historical Note
The rationale for compiling this collection has been lost. The Music Library holds numerous 78 rpm records as historical examples of the labels available and repertoire issued on them.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains 37 78 rpm 10-inch recordings, 1 7-inch 78 rpm recording, 1 5-inch 78 rpm recording, and 1 7-inch 45 rpm recording. The recordings are all commercial releases consisting of classical, ethnic, and popular music.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by recording company and then in numerical order by label number.
Container List
- Brunswick: 8189, 1938, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1938-03-24 (Box 1, Item 01a)
  Matrix number: LA1608A
  Berlin, Irving, 1888-1989:
  Change partners, from Carefree
  Performer(s): Fred Astaire, vocalist; Ray Noble Orchestra
- Brunswick: 8189, 1938, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1938-03-24 (Box 1, Item 01b)
  Matrix number: LA1609
  I used to be color blind, from Carefree
- Brunswick: 8190, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02a)
  Matrix number: LA 1610 A
  Yam, from Carefree
  Performer(s): Fred Astaire, vocalist; Ray Noble and his orchestra
- Brunswick: 8190, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02b)
  Matrix number: LA 1611-A
  Yam Step (As explained by Fred Astaire) from Carefree
- Capitol: none, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Most likely conductor William Steinberg (Box 1, Item 03a-b)
  Matrix number: 9658?
  Interview with Mr. William Steinberge [sic]
- Columbia Graphophone Company: E2935, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; A possible translation of the rest of the label is: Singing Serbian Pavacko Society "Gusle" of New York. For the benefit of the Serbian Red Cross in New York (Box 1, Item 04a)
  Matrix number: 43884
  Smesa srpskih narodnih pesama (Funny Serbian folk songs)
  Performer(s): Servian Chorus, piano accompaniment
- Columbia Graphophone Company: E2935, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; A possible translation of the rest of the label is: Singing Serbian Pavacko Society "Gusle" of New York. For the benefit of the Serbian Red Cross in New York (Box 1, Item 04b)
  Matrix number: 43885
  Ranjenici zvece (something like Wounded rattle) [The first letters of the title are only partially intact due to a label that was attached)
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: 4209-M, 1937, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05a)
  Matrix number: CL 6333
  Rouget de Lisle, Claude Joseph, 1760-1836:
  La Marseillaise
  Performer(s): Choir of the Red Army of the U.S.S.R., directed by A.V. Alexandroff
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: 4209-M, 1937, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05b)
  Matrix number: CL 6334
  Méhul, Etienne Nicolas, 1763-1817:
  Le Chant du Départ
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: 7007-F, 1925?, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Main title in Greek characters (Box 1, Item 06a)
  Matrix number: 89608
  Trelenome Yia Korte
  Performer(s): M. Papagika, soprano, with orchestral accompaniment
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: 7007-F, 1925?, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Main title in Greek characters (Box 1, Item 06b)
  Matrix number: 89612
  M'Ena Fili Sou
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: 36260, 1941?, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Crack in record (Box 1, Item 07a)
  Matrix number: E-63 CO 29874
  Masterpieces of Literature: Volume II: Our American Heritage: Album I: Prose: Selections from the farewell address of George Washington
  Performer(s): Wesley Addy, narrator
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: 36260, 1941?, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Crack in record (Box 1, Item 07b)
  Matrix number: E-64 CO 29877
  Masterpieces of Literature: Volume II: Our American Heritage: Album I: Prose: From the first inaugural address of Thomas Jefferson
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: A 3449, 1921, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1921-06-21 (Box 1, Item 08a)
  Matrix number: 79898
  Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907:
  Solveig's Song from "Peer Gynt Suite No. 11" / Arranged by Eddy Brown
  Arranger or co-composer: Brown, Eddy, 1895-1974
  Performer(s): Eddy Brown, violin; Josef Bonime, piano
- Columbia Phonograph Co.: A 3449, 1921, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1921-06-24 (Box 1, Item 08b)
  Matrix number: 79912
  Chaminade, Cécile, 1857-1944:
  Serenade Espagnole (Spanish Serenade) / transcription by Kreisler
  Arranger or co-composer: Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962
- Continental: C 2004-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09a)
  Matrix number: S80
  Monti, Vittorio, 1868-1922:
  Monty czardas
  Performer(s): Arno Levitch, violin
- Continental: C-2004-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09b)
  Matrix number: S81
  Boulanger, Georges:
  Avant de Mourier
- Csardas: MR-38-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10a)
  Matrix number: 731
  Pali, Pertis, 1906-1947:
  Pertis Pali Keringöje
  Performer(s): Pertis Pali, violin and his band from the Hotel Vadaszkurt, Budapest
- Csardas: MR-38-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10b)
  Matrix number: 732
  Radics, Béla:
  Tatiana keringo
- Emerson Record: 5117, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 5 inches (Box 1, Item 11a)
  Matrix number: 1108-1-11
  Dillon, William A., 1877-:
  My Grandfather's Girl: Baritone solo
  Performer(s): Morton Harvey, baritone
- Emerson Record: No. 7273, 1916, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 7 inches (Box 1, Item 12a)
  Matrix number: 2740
  Jacobs-Bond, Carrie, 1862-1946:
  I love you truly
  Performer(s): Alice Louise Mertens, vocalist
- Emerson Record: No. 7273, 1916, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 7 inches (Box 1, Item 12b)
  Matrix number: 2748-2
  Barth, Con:
  Just you
  Performer(s): Frank Woods, vocalist
- Golden Star Radio Company: GS-2338-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13a)
  Matrix number: GS-2338-A
  Wind in May
  Performer(s): Zhou Xuan, vocalist
- Golden Star Radio Company: GS-2338-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13b)
  Matrix number: GS-2338-B
  Spring at Zhongshan
  Performer(s): Zhou Xuan
- Golden Star Radio Company: M 16A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14a)
  Matrix number: A-5300
  Autumn Moon over the Placid West Lake
- Golden Star Radio Company: M 16 B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14b)
  Matrix number: A-5301
  Return Yan
- Good Time Jazz: EP 1004, 1953, 1 side of 1 45 rpm sound disc; 7 inches; Extended Play, 45 RPM (Box 1, Item 15a)
  Matrix number: LKX-7-D-1
  Ory, Kid, 1886-1973:
  Muskrat Ramble by Kid Ory; Rumpus Rag by Don Ewell
  Performer(s): Don Ewell, piano
- Good Time Jazz: EP 1004, 1953, 1 side of 1 45 rpm sound disc; 7 inches; Extended Play, 45 RPM (Box 1, Item 15b)
  Matrix number: LKX 8
  Ewell, Don:
  Parlor Social by Don Ewell; Wild Man Blues by Morton & Armstrong
  Arranger or co-composer: Morton, Jelly Roll, -1941; Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971-Co-composers
- Gramophone Co.: DA-4905, 1925, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16a)
  Matrix number: OLA 1438-1
  Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924:
  Soir
  Lyricist: Samain, Albert, 1858-1900
  Performer(s): Charles Panzéra, baritone; Magdeleine Panzéra-Baillot, piano
- Gramophone Co.: DA-4905, 1925, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16b)
  Matrix number: OLA 1439-1
  Nocturne
  Lyricist: Villiers de L'Isle-Adam, Auguste, comte de, 1838-1889
- His Master's Voice (Austria): BA 701, 1929?, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1929-05-23 (Box 1, Item 17a)
  Matrix number: BLR 5403
  Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863:
  Stille Nacht, heilige Nacht
  Performer(s): St. Gabriel-Chor [with organ, bells and orchestra]
- His Master's Voice (Austria): BA 701, 1929?, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1929-11-29 (Box 1, Item 17b)
  Matrix number: BN 867
  Glocken der Erzabtei Beuron
  Performer(s): Church bells cast by Georg Wolfart in Lauigen, Bavaria
- His Master's Voice (Berliner Gramophone Co.): 397, 1908, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Beneath His Master's Voice on label: "Victor" (Box 1, Item 18a)
  Matrix number: 18752-A
  Sousa, John Philip, 1854-1932:
  On the Campus-March
  Performer(s): Sousa's Band
- His Master's Voice (Berliner Gramophone Co.): 397, 1908, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Beneath His Master's Voice on label: "Victor" (Box 1, Item 18b)
  Matrix number: 18752-B
  Bullets and Bayonets-March
- His Master's Voice (Gramophone Co.): D.A. 1929, 1949, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; The lyricist is stated as Victoria Gomez Cima, the given name for Victoria De los Angeles (Box 1, Item 19a)
  Matrix number: OEA 13829-1
  Alvarez Quintero, Serafín, 1871-1938:
  Saeta
  Lyricist: Angeles, Victoria de los
  Performer(s): Victoria De los Angeles, soprano; Philharmonia Orchestra; Walter Susskind, conductor
- His Master's Voice (Gramophone Co.): D.A. 1929, 1949, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19b)
  Matrix number: OEA 13830-2
  Campoamor, Manuel:
  Cantares (No. 3 of "Poema en forma de canciones")
  Arranger or co-composer: Turina, Joaquín, 1882-1949
  Performer(s): Victoria de los angeles, soprano; Philharmonia Orchestra; Walter Susskind, conductor
- His Master's Voice (Gramophone Co.): E.G. 3687, 1935, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20a)
  Matrix number: ORA 1075
  Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828:
  An Sylvia
  Performer(s): Karl Erb, tenor; Bruno Seidler-Winkler, pianist
- His Master's Voice (Gramophone Co.): E.G. 3687, 1935, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; From Gesänge, op. 70 (Box 1, Item 20b)
  Matrix number: ORA 1080
  Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897:
  Lerchengesang
  Performer(s): Karl Erb, tenor; Bruno Seidler-Winkler, piano
- His Master's Voice (Gramophone Co.): HE 2272, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21a)
  Matrix number: BLR 5828
  Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899:
  Morgenblätter Walzer
  Performer(s): Marek Weber Orchestra
- His Master's Voice (Gramophone Co.): HE 2272, 1900, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21b)
  Matrix number: BLR 5829
  Du und du (Walzer aust "Die Fledermaus")
- Howell Recording Studio: HTT-101 A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22a)
  Matrix number: HTT 101 A
  Houghton College Trio:
  He Keeps Me Smiling
  Performer(s): Houghton College Trumpet Trio: Ronald Kerr, Robert Mackenzie, and Robert Vogan, trumpets; David Childs, piano
- Howell Recording Studio: HTT-101 B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22b)
  Matrix number: HTT 101 B
  Clayton, Norman J.:
  Now I Belong to Jesus
- London: W. 7148, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; From Piano concerto no. 1 (Box 1, Item 23a)
  Matrix number: DR 7920-2
  Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893:
  Theme from the Concerto in B minor (Tchaikovsky, arr. King Palmer)
  Arranger or co-composer: Palmer, King
  Performer(s): Richard Crean and his Orchestra
- London: W. 7148, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23b)
  Matrix number: DR 7921-2
  Provost, Heinz, 1891-1959:
  Intermezzo from "Escape to Happiness"
- Masterpiece (Musicraft Records): 8531-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24a)
  Matrix number: 1592-1
  Southern Roses
  Performer(s): Concert Orchestra
- Masterpiece (Musicraft Records): 8531-A, 1900, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24b)
  Matrix number: O8-1588-1
  Voices of Spring
- Paraclete: 14 A, 1942, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25a)
  Matrix number: 14A
  Scriabin, Aleksandr Nikolayevich, 1872-1915:
  Preludes opp. 33 (4); 45 (3); 74 (5)
  Performer(s): Samuel Yaffe, piano
- Paraclete: 14 B, 1942, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25b)
  Matrix number: 14B
  Preludes opp. 67 (2); 31 (4) Etude in Fifths
- Parlophone (Odeon Series): P.O. 157, 19--, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1932-04 (Box 1, Item 26a)
  Matrix number: Be 9905
  Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791:
  Magic Flute: Act 2, Pamina's Aria: "Ach ich fühl’s, es ist Verschwunden"
  Lyricist: Schikaneder, Emanuel, 1751-1812
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano; Orchestra, ensemble; Manfred Gurlitt, conductor
- Parlophone (Odeon Series): P.O. 157, 19--, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; *second lyricist Giacosa, Giuseppe, 1847-1906 (Box 1, Item 26b)
  Matrix number: Be 9908
  Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924:
  Madame Butterfly: Act 1, Entrance of Butterfly
  Lyricist: Illica, Luigi, 1857-1919
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano; chorus and orchestra, ensemble; Manfred Gurlitt, conductor
- Parlophone (Odeon Series): P.O. 158, 1900, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27a)
  Matrix number: Be 10388
  Albert, Eugen, 1864-1932:
  Toten Augen "Psyche wandelt durch säulenhallen"
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano; orchestra
- Parlophone (Odeon Series): P.O. 158, 1933, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27b)
  Matrix number: Be 10389
  Marriage of Figaro. Act 4 "O Why so long delay"
  Lyricist: Da Ponte, Lorenzo, 1749-1838
- Parlophone (Odeon Series): P.O. 163, 1950, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28a)
  Matrix number: Be 94952
  Fledermaus. Act 2. Czardas: "Klänge der Heimat"
  Lyricist: Haffner, Karl, 1804-1874 and Genée, Richard, 1823-1895
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano, with Orchestra, Dr. Weissmann, conductor
- Parlophone (Odeon Series): P.O. 163, 1950, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28b)
  Matrix number: Be 9496
  Fledermaus. Act I Couplet: "Mein Herr was dachten Sie von mir?"
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano, with Orchestra, Dr. Weissmann conductor
- RCA Victor: 1616-A, 1933, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29a)
  Matrix number: 1616-A
  Di Capua, Eduardo, 1864-1917:
  O Sole Mio
  Performer(s): Enrico Caruso, tenor; Victor Symphony Orchestra [conducted by Nathaniel Shilkret?]
- RCA Victor: 1616-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29b)
  Matrix number: 1616-B
  Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901:
  Rigoletto-La donna é mobile
  Lyricist: Piave, Francesco Maria, 1810-1876
- RCA Victor: 1901-A, 1938, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1937-10-17 (Box 1, Item 30a)
  Matrix number: 1901A
  Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883:
  Walküre-Du Bist Der Lenz (The Valkyrie-Thou Art the Spring) Act 1
  Lyricist: Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883
  Performer(s): Kirsten Flagstad, soprano; Philadelphia Orchestra; Eugene Ormandy, conductor
- RCA Victor: 1901-B, 1938, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1937-10-17 (Box 1, Item 30b)
  Matrix number: 1901-B
  Lohengrin-Euch lüften die mein klagen (Ye Wandering Breeze)
- RCA Victor: 1738-A, 1936, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1930-04-28 (Box 1, Item 31a)
  Matrix number: BLR 6302
  Zauberflöte-O Isis und Osiris (The Magic Flute-O Osis and Osiris) (Act 2)
  Performer(s): Alexander Kipnis, bass; Berlin State Opera Orchestra; Clemens Schmalstich, conductor
- RCA Victor: 1738-B, 1936, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1931-04-10 (Box 1, Item 31b)
  Matrix number: OD 297
  Entfuhrung aus Dem Serail-Wer Ein Liebchen Hat Gefunden (If a sweetheart one has met with) Act 1
  Lyricist: Stephanie, Gottlieb, 1741-1800
  Performer(s): Alexander Kipnis, bass; Berlin State Opera Orchestra; Erich Orthmann, conductor
- RCA Victor: 1906-A, 1939, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32a)
  Matrix number: 1906-A
  Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856:
  Er und sie (He and she) (op. 78, no. 2) (Orchestrated by Bruno Reibold)
  Lyricist: Kerner, Justinus
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano; Lauritz Melchior, tenor; Orchestra conducted by Bruno Reibold
- RCA Victor: 1906-B, 1939, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32b)
  Matrix number: 1906-B
  Ich denke dein (I think of thee) (op. 78, no. 3)
- RCA Victor: 1907-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Orchestrated by Bruno Reibold (Box 1, Item 33a)
  Matrix number: M 560-3
  Familien-Gemalde (Family Portrait)
  Arranger or co-composer: Reibold, Bruno
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano; Lauritz Melchior, tenor; with orchestra conducted by Bruno Reibold
- RCA Victor: 1907-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Orchestrated by Bruno Reibold (Box 1, Item 33b)
  Matrix number: M 560-4
  1. So Wahr die Sonne Scheinet (Op. 37, No. 12) (True as the Sun Shines) 2. Unterm Fenster (Op. 34, No. 3) (Under the Window)
- RCA Victor: 2109-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1940-02-26 (Box 1, Item 34a)
  Matrix number: M 692-3
  Winterreise (The Winter Journey): 15. Die Krähe (The Raven)
  Lyricist: Müller, Wilhelm, 1794-1827
  Performer(s): Lotte Lehmann, soprano; Paul Ulanowsky, pianist
- RCA Victor: 2109-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1940-02-26 (Box 1, Item 34b)
  Matrix number: M 692-4
  Winterreise (The Winter Journey): 19. Taüschung (Illusion); 22. Mut (Courage)
- RCA Victor: 2110-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35a)
  Matrix number: M 702-1
  Il Seraglio-Act II: Blondine's Aria-Avec de la tendresse (With Tenderness and Coaxing)
  Performer(s): Lily Pons, soprano; Victor Symphony Orchestra
- RCA Victor: 2110-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35b)
  Matrix number: M 702-2
  Paradies, Pietro Domenico, 1707-1791:
  Arietta-Quel Ruscelletto (That Little Brook)
  Performer(s): Lily Pons, soprano; Renaissance Quintet, ensemble
- RCA Victor: M 986, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1941-07-01 (Box 1, Item 36a)
  Matrix number: 10-1122-A
  Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912:
  Élegie (Song of the Mourning)
  Performer(s): Marian Anderson, contralto; William Primrose, violist; Franz Rupp, pianist
- RCA Victor: M 986, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1941-07-01 (Box 1, Item 36b)
  Matrix number: 10-1122-B
  Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943:
  When Night Descends, Op. 4, No. 3
- RCA Victor: 10-1200-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37a)
  Matrix number: 10-1200-A
  Rigoletto Act 1: Questa o quella (The One is as Fair as the Other)
  Performer(s): Jussi Björling, vocalist; Nils Grevillius, conductor
- RCA Victor: 10-1200-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37b)
  Matrix number: 10-1200-B
  Turandot: Act III NESSUN DORMA (None Shall Sleep)
- Royale: 1742, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38a)
  Matrix number: BT 2123
  Träumerei
  Performer(s): Fred Hartley Quintet
- Royale: 1742, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38b)
  Matrix number: BT 2129
  Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894:
  Romance
- Victrola: 502-A, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39a)
  Matrix number: 502-A
  Cottrau, Teodoro, 1827-1879:
  L'Addio a Napoli (Farewell to Naples)
  Performer(s): Enrico Caruso, tenor
- Victrola: 502-B, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39b)
  Matrix number: 502-B
  De Curtis, Ernesto, 1875-1937:
  Canta pe' me (Sing for Me)
  Lyricist: Bovio, Libero, 1883-1942
- RCA Victor: 64758, undated, 1 side of 1 78 rpm sound disc; 10 inches; Recorded: 1917-11-09 (Box 1, Item 40a)
  Matrix number: 64758
  Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930:
  Valse Bluette (Air de ballet)
  Arranger or co-composer: Auer, Leopold, 1845-1930
  Performer(s): Jascha Heifetz, violinist; André Benoist, pianist
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Popular music; Music--20th century
Genres
Sound recordings; Interviews